# SAROJ LAMICHHANE

515 E Halliday St. Apt#1, Pocatello, ID, 83201 929 304-3015 sarojlc15@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/saroj-lamichhane-a1b797119/

# Multiplatform Journalism Major/Idaho State University

0-				
<b>\1</b>	ım	m	าา	<b>1</b> 77
υı	411	ш	aı	. V

Graduating with a Bachelor's degree in communication, media, and persuasion major with an emphasis in Multiplatform Journalism. I also have had a lot of schooling experience in film and radio program marketing as well as production. I have taken many classes in news writing and reporting, screenwriting, television production, communication inquiry and web design. I am seeking a career with storytelling, marketing and communication as the core values.

### Education

2016 - 2020

Bachelor of arts, Mass Communication/Emphasis in Multiplatform Journalism Idaho State University

# Experience

#### October-2017 - Present Production Assistant

#### ISU Bengal Newspaper

- · Improve design layout of the newspaper using InDesign software and implementing Associated Press (AP) style news writing techniques in articles, cut lines and headlines.
- · Composed a new 'Entertainment' section in the paper by converting and by cropping pictures into cyan, magenta, yellow, and black (CMYK) format to cover fun events organized on and off-campus.

# December 2016 -

# Communication Intern

# Present

## Continuing Education and Workforce Training

- · Recorded and edited promotional and educational videos for classes at Idaho State University's Workforce Training Department.
- · Volunteered supervisor complete projects on time by mastering professional video editing skills in pre-production, color correction, color grading, advanced editing techniques and animation.
- · The department extended my internships even after the summer for one more year.

# June 2014 - December 2016

#### Media Consultant

#### Aasusen Films Production Ltd

- · Helped to collect the highest gross collection of \$4 million dollars by playing a significant role in publicity of movie - "Prem Geet".
- · Supervised 7 sponsored program presenters during the promotional campaigns and monitored their tasks every day before the release of the movie.

# February 2013 -

# Program Producer, Host, and Mixing Console Operator

## December-2016

## Radio Rajdhani and Mero FM, Nepal

· Wrote scripts for ads and programs, presented three shows: Way to Cinema, College College Ma, Head or Tail and Filmy Kura and worked as a technician to handle mixing console in live broadcasts.

#### Honors

# The Intern of the Month, February 2018

Career Center at ISU

- Recognized by the department as an outstanding CPI interns by going above and beyond my internship duties
- Awarded a certificate, CPI swag, as well as a Chartwells voucher
- Featured in the career center website, the Idaho State Journal as well as ISU Headlines

# Member of the Club Award, April 2018

Student Acquisition and Cultural Assimilation Association

• Student Acquisition and Cultural Assimilation at Idaho State University nominated me as an active member of the club in the Office of Equal Opportunity Affirmation Action and Diversity's cultural celebration event.

#### Volunteer -

April 2015 - November Event Co-ordinator

2015

SAHARA Group Nepal

Organized poem competition and art education for high school students in Rasuwa district of Nepal.

June 2015 - October

Surveyor

2016

World Wide Fund, Nepal

Successfully complected a communication research on a biodiversity project for high school students in Kathmandu, Nepal.

# Biography

Saroj Lamichhane, junior at Idaho State University, is a communication major with an emphasis on multiplatform journalism at Idaho State University. He is working as an intern with CEWT for videographer and video editor position. He is also serving a position of communication officer for Advertising Federation and communication officer and fundraiser for SACAA. Previously, he worked as a public co-ordination for Nepalese Student Association during his first year in the college.

Lamichhane came from Nepal to ISU with an aim to be a journalist for broadcasting and paper media. He wants to be a foreign correspondent and a television presenter in a recognized media after graduating from ISU. He had also worked as a radio presenter in Nepal during his high school, and involved in media marketing and writing for the film industry.

Lamichhane had won "The Best Entertainer of The Year" award in 2014 in his high school by entertaining audiences through the caricature of his teachers and creative speech on the stage. His friends and colleagues were shocked by his talent.

Lamichhane has also been making short documentaries, marketing videos and flyers, and interviews video since past few years. Lamichhane has a good knowledge of Adobe Creative Cloud, and for this, he is thankful to his supervisor, Paul M. Dickey, who works as a video instructor at CEWT.

Storytelling, marketing, reporting, cinematography, movie direction, radio or television presenter, and advanced graphics and video editing are some of his favorite jobs that he would not give up to anything. Lamichhane will graduate in 2019 with a degree of bachelors in communication media and persuasion in Multiplatform Journalism.

#### **Portfolios**

# 1. Talk Show at KISU Broadcast Studio-Sustainable Development Goal.

The ISU Bengal Newspaper journalist Saroj Lamichhane talks to the director of Admission office over International Program Office, Shawn Bascom, and the Associate Professor in the Department of Management, Dr. Jeff Street of Idaho State University about the United Nation's 4th goal for sustainable development, also known as 2030 agenda of U.N.-- Quality Education. In this show, Lamichhane discuss on ongoing education system in the U.S. and global educational institution position for maintaining the quality education. Enjoy the show!

#### Click Here to Watch the Video

# 2. Marketing Video - Construction Combine Invitation to Idahoans

Lamichhane creates a concept of presentation video for a marketing purpose to Idaho State University Continuing Education and Workforce Training, the Construction Combine Event. In the video, Scott Stephens, the business consultant at CEWT and Brad Landon, the manager at Home Depot in Pocatello invites Idahoans to join the event.

#### Click Here to Watch the Video

#### 3. Documentary - One Day from New York

Lamichhane travels to New York to make his dream documentary of the city. This eight minute feature video could be something informative to those who are planning to visit New York city or those who wants to be informed about the city. He uses Iphone 7 to shoot the video as he didn't have DSLR on his own at the time. He uses Adobe Premiere Pro and After Effects to edit those footage. He does the narration on his own, goes inside the tramway in the Roosevelt Island to get a skyview shot that he still thinks incredible. He continues uploading series of travel videos and documentaries later then too.

## **Click Here to Watch the Video**

#### 4. Features Blog - Entrepreneurship, Travel, Sports, and Life

As a multimedia journalist, Lamichhane discovers news writing and reporting is not merely sufficient for his professional communication career. He takes features writing course to be able to reveal place, business, event, people, history in his writing by creating exposition, dialogue, description, mood, and tension.

#### **Click Here to Open the Blog**

#### 5. Design Portfolio - ISU Bengal Newspaper

Lamichhane uses InDesign software to create the production layout for the newspaper. He worked in a team of adviser, section editor, photo editor, advertising manager, and editor-in-chief to create a content on their principal. He has also been making posters, flyers and magazines for different clubs and organization on campus.

# **Click Here to Open the Design Portfolio**

# 6. Reporting - Earthquake Victims in Nepal Fight for Settlement

The reporting brings the situation of the survivors in 7.5 magnitude of earthquake bang in the eastern part of Nepal. Lamichhane goes to the Nuwakot region of Nepal to raise sufferers' voice to the government. Over 9,000 people were killed in the disaster.

#### **Click Here to Watch the Video**